LAND OF MIRE MARE
© 2014 by Luca Bordoni


NOTICE

This game has to be considered as a tribute, its inspired by the unreleased Mire Mare game & characters created by Ultimate Play The Game in golden 80's.

In the Land of Mire Mare three volcanoes are on the brink to burn the whole territory. In order to avoid a disaster, Sabreman will have to find and use three magic jewels.


INSTRUCTIONS

The mission is to find three enchanted jewels which have the power to turn off volcanoes, then throw them into the Well of Mire Mare, in order to break the curse.

Sabreman's vital energy is represented by a water bar, which will decrease when a collision occurs with an enemy.

Each jewel is defended by a deadly Guardian: a Knight, a Gargoyle and a Fire Eagle. Watch out for the Guardians, because they are invulnerable!

Along the way, the adventurer can bump into strange Mushrooms: they give 30°/o of chance to be recharged and score 100 points. But if it's not a lucky moment, the rest of chances will bring to death.

Various collectibles can be found around the land. Three of them represent special pledges which can be exchanged to pick up jewels, the others will only increase the score.

Once a pledge is exchanged with a jewel, it will be no longer possible to pick up the same object. If inventory is empty, jewels cannot be collected.

Enemies can be defeated by three different weapons: 

SWORD - defeats most of the monsters;

AXE - useful to extinguish fire flames;

STAFF - defeats gas bubbles.

A lava hourglass is shown at the bottom of the gatneplay, it represents a timer before the next volcano explosion. The hourglass countdown refreshes every time a jewel is thrown into the pit.


Controls:
Q - up
A - down
O - left
P - right
SPACE - Use weapons/Pick up/Exchange objects

Good luck!

Atom version done by Kees van Oss.

===================================================================
System requirements:
===================================================================

- Standard Acorn Atom
- 32 KB RAM
- 8 KB video RAM (#8000-#9FFF)
- Joystick connected to keyboard matrix (Optional)
- Joystick connected to PORTB AtoMMC interface (Optional)

===================================================================
Joystick (optional JOYMMC):
===================================================================

The joystick is connected to PORTB of the AtoMMC interface with 
softwareversion 2.9. The connections are like this:

AtoMMC  Joystick
-----------------
 PB0  -  Right
 PB1  -  Left
 PB2  -  Down
 PB3  -  Up
 PB4  -  Jump
 PB5  -  nc
 PB6  -  nc
 PB7  -  nc

 GND  -  GND

If direction is active, bit = 1

===================================================================
Joystick (optional JOYKEY):
===================================================================

The joystick is connected parallel to row 1 of the keyboard matrix.

    nokey - fire
	G - Right
	3 - Left
	- - Down
	Q - Up

===================================================================
Tape/Disk and AtoMMC version:
===================================================================

Tape version:

  MIREMARE.CSW, Tapefile for Atomulator, to start the game, type: *RUN"AGD"

Disk version:

  MIREMARE.DSK, Diskfile for emulators, to start the game, type *RUN"MMRUN"

AtoMMC version:

  MMRUN  = Basic introscreen
  MMSCR  = Titlescreen
  MMCODE = Gamecode

  To start the game, type: *MMRUN

